You may have been waiting for when I was going to start talking about Swiss manufactured clocks.
The fact is, the Swiss didn't really make that many clocks.
They're much more famous for their watch making industry.
So, I'm often asked, "Well, how 'bout Switzerland?"
You know, "Where's all the Swiss clocks?"
Again, not many of them.
They did make this style of clock, called the Neuchatel clock, it goes back to the seventeen hundreds, but they actually still make reproductions of them today.
This is a form of bracket clock.
So when we were talking about bracket clocks before, you would know that underneath this would have been a similarly painted shelf or bracket that the clock would sit on.
And when you buy the reproductions now is Switzerland, perhaps, they always come with that same bracket, with the same floral paintings and things going on there as well.
So there are Swiss clocks, not that many of them.
But a much larger category of Swiss clocks, actually were small clocks that were more similar to watches in construction and size than they were to clocks.
This is a travel clock, probably from the nineteen-twenties, made in Switzerland, but it really is just a large pocket watch essentially, that's built in to a folding case.
So these are often in leather, sometimes in silver, but probably the bulk of Swiss clock-making would be in small clocks like this.